《赛艇男孩》
用力
Press.
蹬腿
Legs through.
保持一致
Stay together.
同步
As one.
破水，划
In. Through.
蹬腿
Legs through.
天啊
Oh, man!
搞什么鬼？
What the heck?
我发誓那小子会要了我的命
I swear that boy's gonna be the death of me.
每次我修好了，他又会撕掉
Every time I fix it, he rips it again.
（西雅图，华盛顿州1936年）
工程设计和其他创意领域
Engineering design is different
有点不同
from other areas of creativity
在这一点上，你必须有能力真正建造出
in that, you must be able to actually build
你的创意
what you imagine.
然后确保它按照你的设计方式运行
And then make sure it works as you designed.
设计过程有助于结构化引导
The design process is structured to help direct
你的创造力
your creativity.
现在...
Now, uh...
你想成为哪种工程师？
What kinda engineer you wanna be?
我想当个机械工程师，因为我喜欢造东西
I'm thinking mechanical for me, 'cause I like building things.
－嗯哼　－你想成为...
- Mm-hmm. - You wanna partner up on...
两位先生有什么想和我们分享的吗？
Something you two gentlemen would like to share with us?
或者我可以继续了吗？
Or can I continue?
对不起
Sorry.
－谢谢　－好极了，谢谢
- Thank you. - Awesome. Thank you.
好吧，我还要一个人
Okay, I just need one more.
让我看看
Let's see.
你
Uh, you.
今天就到这儿吧，伙计们，对不起
That's all I need today, fellas. Sorry.
－早安　－早上好
- Morning. - Morning.
这是我今天早上收到的
This was in my box this morning.
好吧，看来你还欠着本学期的
Okay, it looks like you still owe a balance
一点学费
on this semester.
对，我已经付了一半了
Yeah, well, I paid half already
他们说我可以稍后再付另一半
and they said I could pay the other half later.
兰茨先生，恐怕已经到期了
Afraid later has arrived, Mr. Rantz.
也许干点兼职会有帮助
Maybe a part-time job would help.
我一直在找
I've been looking.
走廊尽头有一块公告牌
Well, there's a board down the hall.
我可以给你延期两周
I can give you two weeks.
之后，您就需要考虑
After that, you will need to consider
其他的教育选项了
other educational options.
谢谢
Thanks.
浪费时间，我打遍了这里所有的电话
It's a waste of time. I called every number up here.
甚至那份保姆工作都问过
And that nanny job,
在学期开始前就已全部招满了
all filled before semester even started.
我每天都来查查，想抢个新机会
I check every day to get a jump on a new one,
但是一个机会都没有
but there hadn't been any.
在我租得起房子之前，我只能住在姑妈家
I'm staying with my aunt till I can afford a place.
每天都要花上半天时间从衣服上扯猫毛
I spend half my day pulling cat hair off of my clothes.
我讨厌猫
I hate cats.
你喜欢吗？
You like 'em?
我是说猫
Cats, I mean.
我，呃，从来没怎么考虑过它们
I, uh, never thought much about 'em.
我讨厌他们
I hate 'em.
我想我在课堂上见过你
Thought I saw you in class.
－你还记得我吗？－嗯
- You remember me? - Mm-hmm.
好吧，那我叫什么名字？
All right. Then, what's my name?
乔伊斯・西姆达斯
Uh, Joyce Simdars.
－你是乔・兰兹　－嗯哼
- And you're Joe Rantz. - Uh-huh.
我记得，因为四年级的时候
I remember because you had a huge crush on me
你暗恋我来着
in the fourth grade.
－不，我没有　－你有
- No, I didn't. - Yeah, yeah, you did.
你给我做了张漂亮的小卡片
You made me this pretty little card
里面夹着几朵小花
with some flowers stuffed in it.
就在我家搬去奥林匹亚之前
Right before my family went away to Olympia.
－啊　－你是那种一紧张就
- Uh... - Are you one of those people
吃不下东西的人吗？
who can't eat when you're nervous?
－我没紧张　－没？
- I'm not nervous. - No?
那么，你在这里做什么，乔？
So, what are you doing here, Joe?
我在这学习，呃，工程学
I'm trying to learn, uh, engineering.
嗯
Hmm.
我要当老师
I'm gonna be a teacher.
不过，来这里主要还是为了离家远点
Mostly here just to get away from home, though.
你还记得我妈妈吗？
You remember my mother?
算是吧，她手里总是拿着本《圣经》
Sorta. Always had a Bible in her hand.
是啊
Yeah.
除非她扔过来砸你
Unless she's throwing it at you.
你喜欢划艇吗？
You like rowboats?
你知道的，坐在上面划水那种
You know, like, paddlin' 'em.
－你是谁？－我是罗杰
- Who's this? - I'm Roger.
嗨，罗杰，我是乔伊斯
Hi, Roger. I'm Joyce.
这是乔，但他现在不太爱说话
This is Joe, but he's not real talkative right now
因为他有点紧张
'cause he's a little bit nervous.
－不，我没有，我没有　－他有点紧张
- No, I'm not. No, I'm not. - He is a little nervous.
我不紧张
I'm not nervous.
如果你会划，我们也许能赚点钱
We might be able to make some money if you can row.
－乔伊斯，好了吗？－哦，得走了，孩子们
- Joyce, you ready? - Oh. Gotta go, boys.
很高兴再次见到你，乔
Nice seeing you again, Joe.
罗杰
Roger.
顺便说一句
By the way,
你从那段暗恋中走出来过吗？
did you ever get over that crush?
来吧，我们走
Come on, let's go.
她很好看，是吧？
She's a looker, huh?
那么，赚钱是怎么回事？
So, what's that about making some money?
对，赛艇队
Yeah, the rowing team.
只要进了队，你就算得到了一份兼职
You're on it, you get a part-time job
还包括一个便宜的住的地方
including a cheap place to live.
我就可以摆脱那些猫了
I could get free of them cats.
你要做的就是进队
All you gotta do is make the team.
这有什么难的？
How hard can that be?
有多少人能进队？
How many make the team?
嘿，有多少，呃...
Hey, how many, uh...
要选多少人？
How many fellas get picked?
我想是8个
Eight, I think.
8个？
Eight?
他说什么？
What's he say?
他不知道
He didn't know.
好了，听着
All right, listen up.
我是乌尔布里克森教练
I'm Coach Ulbrickson.
那是博尔斯教练
Well, that's Coach Bolles,
布朗教练
Coach Brown.
现在，你们来这里，是因为我们正在遴选
Now, you're all here because we're looking
8名最有资格的年轻人来组成初级队
for the eight most qualified young men to fill out JV boat.
这意味着你们中的大多数人都不会被选中
That means most of you will not be chosen.
事实上，你们中的大多数人很可能会
In fact, the majority of you will most likely
在接下来的几周内自行离开
walk away on your own within the next few weeks,
因为你们的身体会受伤
'cause your bodies will hurt,
精神会疲倦
minds will tire,
你会认定你要与世界上
and you'll decide this dream of yours
最优秀的赛艇选手同台竞技的梦想
to compete against the greatest crews in the world
就是不值得的
is just not worth it.
这并不丢人
There's no shame in that.
8人赛艇
Eight-man crew
是世界上最难的团队运动
is the most difficult team sport in the world.
普通人的身体根本无法承受这些
The average human body is just not meant for such things.
根本做不了这种事
It's just not capable of such things.
但普通人是不可能在我的艇上找到座位的
But average is not gonna get a seat on my boat.
所以，祝你好运
So, good luck.
好的，分成两队
Okay. Fall into two lines.
左边是注册生，右边是自费生
Registration on the left. Uniforms on the right.
说得真好，教练
That was a beautiful speech, Coach.
－姓名？－乔・兰兹
- Name? - Uh, Joe Rantz.
乔，你以前当过艇员吗？
Joe, you ever crewed before?
呃...呃...
Uh... Um...
划艇，你划过艇吗？
Row. You ever rowed before?
不，不，呃...
No. No. Uh...
入队后这份工作的薪水是多少？
How much does the job pay once you're on the team?
去那边拿你的装备
Go pick up your gear over there.
－去右边，下一个　－姓名？
- To your right. Next. - Name?
罗杰・莫里斯
Roger Morris.
罗杰，你以前当过艇员吗？
Roger, you ever crewed before?
不
No.
好的
All right.
到对面领装备
Pick up your gear across the way.
你们将被分成几个小组
You'll be divided into groups
并在训练坞进行轮换
and rotate through training stations.
叫到自己的号码时，跟着教练走
When you hear your number called, follow the coach.
1到16号，你们跟着我
One through 16, you're with me,
17到32跟着马修斯教练
17 through 32 with Coach Matthews,
33至48号跟我
33 to 48 with me.
排好队
Line up.
你知道我们要干什么去吗？
You got any idea what we're in for?
我不知道
I don't know.
很好，我也是
Good. Me either.
1到16号，快点
One through 16, come on.
一般成年男子有能力
The average adult man is capable
每分钟吸入大约四升氧气
of taking in roughly four liters of oxygen per minute.
一个桨手必须达到8个人的消耗量
An oarsman must be able to consume as much as eight.
你必须让你的身体学会这种能力
You have to teach your bodies to do that.
－我们做50个俯卧撑
- We'll do 50 push-ups,
然后是50个仰卧起坐和50组往返跑
followed by 50 sit-ups and 50 jacks.
我们将继续做50组
We'll keep doing sets of 50
直到换训练坞的时候
till it's time to change stations.
每边8个
Eight on each side.
脚放在踏板上
Feet in stretchers.
系上鞋带
Lace 'em up.
让我们把老尼禄号划出去
Let's take Old Nero out.
好了，听我口令，挺直腰板，用你的腿
All right, on my count, straight backs, use your legs.
12号！别光拍水，转动你的手腕
Twelve! Don't just slap the water. Roll your wrists.
起，躺
Up, down.
四，五，六，七
Four, five, six, seven,
八，九，十
eight, nine, ten.
一，二，三，四
Stroke, two, three, four.
入水，推进，完成，归位
Catch, drive, finish, recovery.
到码头了，所有人下艇
Next station. Everybody out.
起，躺
Up, down.
交换
Switch!
都准备好了吗？
All set?
起，躺
Up, down.
运桨分四个步骤，先生们
There's four parts to a stroke, gentlemen,
不是三个，好吗？
not three, okay?
入水，推进，完成，归位
Catch, drive, finish, and recovery.
一个都不能少
You can't skip any of 'em.
你们知道我们为什么没走直线吗？
And you know why we're not going in a straight line?
因为22号
'Cause number 22 here
是这里唯一一个在听我说话的人
is the only one that's listening to me.
入水，推进
Catch, drive,
完成，归位
finish, recovery.
这样好多了
That's better.
好的，让我们加快节奏到18拍
All right. Let's pick up the pace to 18.
这里有很多好木材啊，教练
Lot of tall timber in this bunch, Coach.
那边的孩子几乎没有能比得上你们校队的
Few boys there could even push your varsity crew.
才第一天，还很难说呢
It's hard to judge off one day.
不过，你还要看到什么
Still, you had to see enough
才能让你开怀大笑？
to make you almost finally crack a smile?
赛季结束后我会告诉你的，啊？
Yeah, I'll let you know at the end of the season, huh?
奥运年，今年
Olympic year, this year,
所以假如理想的话，他们的训练时间要比以往更长
so ideally, they'll stretch longer than most.
奥运年？我都没有意识到
Olympic year? I didn't realize.
我在加州大学和埃布莱特教练谈过了
I spoke with Coach Ebright down in Cali.
他肯定意识到了
He's sure aware of it.
他对自己的机会也很有信心
Feels good about his chances, too.
哦，是吗？
Oh, yeah?
有什么第一印象想报道出来的吗？
Any first impressions you'd like to see in print?
你知道我不看报纸的，洛伊尔
You know I don't read the paper, Royal.
对不起，教练
Excuse me, Coach.
如果你想问诀窍，那就与其他人一样
If you're looking for tips, you're gonna have to get 'em
在训练中去找吧
in practice like everybody else.
不，先生，我只是想知道会给多少工资
No, sir. I was just wondering how much this paid.
再说一遍？
Say again?
他们说，如果能入选，还能得到一份工作？
They said there was a job included if you make the team?
我只想知道够不够支付
I just need to know if it's gonna cover
我剩下的学费
the rest of my tuition.
是的，我肯定是够的
Yeah, I'm sure it will.
嘿，你先集中精力看能不能入选吧，孩子
Hey, you just concentrate for now on making the squad, son.
谢谢你，先生
Thank you, sir.
现在，我打赌这个问题
Now, there's a question I bet
那些常春藤联盟的教练们永远也不会遇到
those Ivy League coaches never get.
说到
Speakin' of,
我当然希望今年能比去年更好
I sure hope this year goes better than the last.
没有人比我更支持你的孩子们了
No one's rooting for your boys more than me.
－祝你好运，教练　－你也是，洛伊尔
- Good luck, Coach. - And you, Royal.
你去吃东西吗？
Did you go grab some food?
啊，我不饿
Ah, I'm not hungry.
如果你想要吃的话，我拿的足够我们俩吃的
I got enough for us both if you want it.
没那么饿
Not that hungry.
回头见
I'll see you later.
我很感激
I appreciate it.
给你
There you go.
－给你，先生　－谢谢
- Here you go, sir. - Thank you.
鸡肉怎么样？
How's your chicken?
很不错，谢谢
Great. Thanks.
是吗，你吃的是猪排
Yeah, that's a pork chop you're eating.
啊
Ah.
对不起
Sorry.
所以，我今天见到了洛伊尔・布鲁姆
So, I saw Royal Brougham today.
他还特意告诉我
And he made sure to tell me
凯・埃布莱特的球队今年实力强劲
that Ky Ebright's squad is strong this year.
加州大学队一直很强的
Cal is always strong.
而你一直在担心
And you always worry.
这帮新孩子们看起来怎么样？
How'd your new boys look?
现在下结论还为时过早
Well, it's too early to say.
人倒是有很多
There's definitely a lot of 'em.
很好，有这么大的马场可供选择
That's good. Nice big stable to choose from.
－如果有足够多的能坚持到最后　－最好的就会
- If enough of them last. - The best ones will.
－就像你一样　－嗯
- Just like you did. - Mm.
你怎么了？
What's wrong with you?
没什么，只是有点僵硬
Nothing, just a little stiff.
嗯，看到了，怎么搞的？
Yeah, looks it. How come?
划艇划到我们差点没命
Rowed boats till it almost killed us.
什么？
What?
课本第43页
Page 43 in your texts.
因此，在解决框架问题时
So, in solving the framework,
反射意味着什么？
what does it mean to reflect?
对不起，年轻人
Excuse me, young man.
要不要我小声点，好让你休息？
Would you like me to speak quieter so you can rest?
我感觉这可能是个陷阱问题
I feel like that's maybe a trick question.
－安静
- Quiet!
要么专心听讲，要么回家睡觉
Pay attention or go home to sleep.
你不能在这睡大觉
You can't do both in here.
不客气，乔・兰茨
You're welcome, Joe Rantz.
谢谢
Thank you.
三
Three.
四
Four.
推，然后拉，推...
Push, then pull. Push...
起，躺
Up, down!
48号和12号在艇头
48 and 12 on the bow.
是的，我想...
Yeah. I'm thinkin'...
把莫里斯放在兰茨身后的六号位？
What about Morris in the six behind Rantz?
跟上我的节奏
Keep time with me.
一，二，三，四，一，二...
Stroke, two, three, four. Stroke, two...
来吧，孩子们！谁更想要？
Come on, boys! Who wants it more?
继续蹬腿
Keep driving those legs!
不要让22号打败你！
Do not let 22 beat you!
你还记得我吗？
You still remember me?
嗯
Mm-hmm.
不确定
Wasn't sure.
最近很少见到你
Haven't seen you much lately.
我只是一直在忙事情
I just been busy with stuff.
－赛艇？－大部分是
- Rowing stuff? - Mostly.
嗯
Hmm.
我听罗杰说，他们今天要公布队员名单
I heard Roger say that they're announcing the team today.
你能进吗？
Are you gonna make it?
有很多人都想进
There's lot of guys tryin'.
等你进了，你想带我去坐艇兜风吗？
You wanna take me on a boat ride when you do?
当然
Sure.
先生们
Gentlemen,
感谢大家参与
I wanna thank you all for comin' out
并全力以赴
and giving your best effort.
你们留在这里的每一个人
Every single one of you left standing
都有令人钦佩的表现
has performed admirably.
遗憾的是，你们中只有少数人可以被选中留下来继续
Unfortunately, only a few of you can be chosen to continue.
博尔斯教练
Coach Bolles.
休谟
Hume.
亨特
Hunt.
麦克米伦
McMillin.
戴
Day.
莫里斯
Morris.
怀特
White.
亚当
Adam.
兰茨
Rantz.
科伊，你是替补
Coy, you're the reserve.
感谢你们付出的时间和努力
We thank the rest of you for your time and your effort.
那好吧
All right, then.
去庆祝吧
Go and celebrate.
明天水上见
I will see you on the water tomorrow.
干得好
Well done.
这是我最喜欢的部分
That's my favorite part.
来吧，孩子们
Come on, boys.
我们走吧
Let's go.
现在把浆举起来
Now lift 'em up.
这家伙满嘴都是他的道奇
It's all this guy talks about, his Dodge.
嘿，听着，我划得太多了
Hey, listen, I've done so much rowing.
我就知道你会入选的
I knew you'd made it.
我很高兴我们中有个人做到了
I'm glad one of us did.
啊，你的入选一直都是稳的
Ah, you were always in the bag.
当教练叫到我的名字时，我的膝盖差点跪下了
When Coach called my name, my knees almost buckled.
不知道他们会给我们安排什么位置
I wonder what seats they'll put us in.
我只想坐在领桨手的位置上
I just want the stroke.
那是休姆的位置，我打包票
That's Hume's seat. Guaranteed.
嘿，你不是哑巴吧？
Hey, you're not a mute, are you?
因为我从没听你说过一句话
'Cause I've never once heard you say nothin'.
不是
No.
像他那样划桨，他不需要会说话
He doesn't need to talk, the way he pulls that oar.
是啊，查克，也许你应该多划桨少说话
Yeah, Chuck, maybe you should pull more and talk less,
如果你想坐那个领桨手座位
you want that stroke seat.
我不在乎他们把我放在哪里
I don't care where they put me,
只要我在就行
as long as I'm in there somewhere.
我们都会在的
We're all in there somewhere.
是啊
Yeah.
向华盛顿鞠躬
Bow down to Washington
穿金戴银者威风凛凛
Mighty are the men who wear the purple and the gold
我们高兴地欢迎他们加入胜利者的行列
Joyfully we welcome them within the victor's fold
我们将把自己的名字刻在名人堂里
We will carve our names in the Hall of Fame
为了保留我们奉献的记忆
To preserve the memory of our devotion
所以，上天保佑华盛顿的敌人
So, heaven help the foes of Washington
他们在强大的华盛顿脚下瑟瑟发抖
They're trembling at the feet of mighty Washington
我们的小伙子在那里敲钟，他们的战斗血性出类拔萃
Our boys are there with bells, Their fighting blood excels
把他们推过界线比通过....
It's harder to push them over the lines than pass...
－嘿　－嗨
- Hey. - Hi.
你...
You, uh...
你想去赛艇上坐坐吗？
You wanna go for a boat ride?
现在？
Now?
是啊
Yeah.
好吧
Yeah, okay.
入水，推进
Catch, drive,
完成，归位
finish, recovery.
在重来一遍之前，你必须做完所有四个步骤
You gotta do all four before you can start again.
好多了，下一步你要翻桨了
That's better. You gotta feather next.
翻桨？什么是翻桨？
Feathering? What's feather?
看这里
Here, look.
你滚动你的手腕
You roll your wrists
转动艇桨
to spin the oar.
－看到了吗？－嗯
- You see? - Mm.
现在，再试一次
Now, try again.
你是天生的
You're a natural.
我以为你说要带我坐着艇兜风去
I thought you said you were gonna take me on a boat ride.
好吧，坐过去点
All right, scooch over.
好的
All right.
你喜欢吗？划艇？
Do you like it? Rowing?
还行
Well,
得到一份工作
gettin' a job out of it.
还有一个房间，所以，我猜
And a room. So, I guess.
还有谁入选了？
Who else made the team?
罗杰，矮子和其他一些人
Roger, Shorty, some others.
你知道，他们会在广播里播报比赛
You know, they put the races on the radio.
每个人都在听
Everybody listens.
他们拍了一些照片
Yeah, they took, uh, some photos.
－问了一堆问题　－什么样的问题？
- Asked a bunch of questions. - What kinds of questions?
就是，你知道
It's just, you know,
我们来自哪里，诸如此类的
where we're from, stuff like that.
你告诉他们事实了吗？
Did you tell them the truth?
嗯，差不多吧
Mm. Mostly.
你们都会出名的
You're all gonna be famous.
然后你就真的会忘记我了
Then you really will forget about me.
就算我想，我觉得我也做不到
I don't think I could if I tried.
你得把我们划回岸上
You get to row us back to shore.
我们早上还有课
We have class in the morning.
－你想要哪张床？－我不在乎
- Which bed you want? - Couldn't care less.
哦，不错
Oh, nice.
我们可以留着这些，对吗？
We get to keep these, right?
只要我们还在队里
Long as we stay on the team.
艇上的每个座位都有自己的用途
Each seat on the boat has its own purpose.
就像一匹高大赛马身上的8个独立部位
Like eight separate parts of one great racehorse.
莫里斯在一号，戴在二号
Morris in one, Day in two,
亚当在三号
and Adam in the three.
你们的技术要让艇保持正确的航向
Your technique will keep the boat on its proper course.
而四，五，六就像是引擎舱
And four, five, and six are like the engine room.
这是力量源泉
That is the power.
怀特，麦克米伦和亨特
White, McMillin, and Hunt.
现在，兰茨是我们的七号
Now, Rantz is our seven.
所以，你和休姆，领桨员，一起设定节奏
So, you set the pace with Hume, the stroke.
每一匹好赛马都有一个骑师
And every good racehorse has a jockey.
格伦・莫里...
Glenn Morry...
来吧，格伦
Come on, Glenn.
是我们的舵手
is our coxswain.
现在，他指挥的策略
Now, he calls the strategy
是由我和博尔斯教练设定的
set up by myself and Coach Bolles.
他想让你们跑的时候，就会给你们松缰绳
He'll give you rein when he wants you to run,
他会把缰绳拉紧，让你们慢下来
he'll pull you back to slow you down.
一旦时机成熟，他就会拿出鞭子
And when the time is right, he'll get out his whip.
嘿，伙计们
Hey, fellas.
好了，该下水了
Okay, time to get in the water.
我们再来一次！
Let's go again!
嘿，菜鸟队
Hey, junior boat,
第一天，累吗？
you tired after your first day?
他不会成功的，别这么认真
He'll never make it. Don't take it so hard.
嘿，你去哪儿？回来
Hey, where you going? Come back.
我讨厌那些混蛋
I hate those assholes.
你得学会掌握自己的节奏
You gotta learn to pace yourself.
－乔，对吧？　－嗯哼
- It's Joe, isn't it? - Mm-hmm.
你们大多数人都对艇不感兴趣
Most of you boys don't have an interest in a boat
直到你坐在里面
until you can sit in it.
你喜欢做木工活吗？
You like to work with wood?
是的，我父亲做过一些
Yeah, my father did some.
他以前会做些东西
He used to make things.
不是这种，就是门廊之类的东西
Nothing like this, just porches and stuff.
有一次，我帮他修好了一艘旧独木舟
I helped him fix up an old canoe once.
我相信他和你的母亲现在一定为你感到非常骄傲
I'm sure he and your mother must be very proud of you now.
加入赛艇队
Making the team.
这是给你们的
This is for you boys.
你们的比赛艇
Your racing shell.
随时欢迎你来帮我一把
Always welcome to give me a hand with it.
如果你有空的话
If you find some free time.
不，我不是说现在
No, I didn't mean right now.
你今晚应该好好休息
You should rest up tonight.
我没事
I'm okay.
技术比力量更重要
Technique is more important than power.
你必须学会划出完美的桨法
You have to be able to pull a perfect oar,
一桨接着一桨
stroke after stroke.
所谓摇摆
It's called swing.
当8个人全都划得如此整齐划一
When all eight are rowing in such perfect unison
没有任何一个动作
that no single action
和艇上其他人的不同步
is out of sync with the rest of the boat.
这样你们的力量就不会互相抵消了
Then you aren't fighting each other.
艇跑起来更省力
You're moving with less effort.
你划出的每一桨都相当于
Each one of your strokes is worth
另一艘艇的一桨半
one and a half of the other boat's.
大多数艇员从未领略过
Most crews never find it.
但当他们领略到时
But when they do,
赛艇与其说是一项运动，不如说是一首诗
rowing is more poetry than sport.
怀特和戴，交换位置
White and Day, switch.
兰茨，亚当
Rantz, Adam,
换回来
switch back.
划！
Row!
－划！－来吧
- Row! - Come on!
划！划过湖面
Row! Row through the lake!
划！用力
Row! More!
怎么，你们把最近三年学过的东西
What, did you forget everything you learned
都忘了吗？
in the last three years?
布朗，你还在划空
Brown, you're still skying.
比林斯，你是领桨员吗？你在赶
Billings, are you the stroke? You're rushing.
你身后有七个人，都被你带得很赶
You have seven men behind you, all chasing the boat.
34桨
34 strokes.
你们划34桨没问题
You're fine at 34 strokes.
再高一点，你们就崩溃了
Anything higher and you fall apart.
34桨，你们赢不了加州大学
34 strokes, you don't beat Cal.
34桨
34 strokes,
在波基普西你们赢不了
you don't win at Poughkeepsie.
你们肯定去不了德国
You certainly don't get to Germany.
你们知道34桨能打败谁吗？
You know who you beat with 34 strokes?
初级队
The JV boat.
只是可能
Maybe.
你们还在等什么？回到艇上去
What are you guys waiting for? Get back in the boat.
你们，你们要回到那里去
You guys, you're gonna get back out there
然后再做一次，直到做对为止！
and you're gonna do it again until you get it right!
希望我没有打扰你，艾尔
Hope I'm not intruding, Al.
不，本，进来吧，请坐
Not at all, Ben. Come on in. Take a seat.
正是时候
Great timing.
刚好在查看准备送交贵委员会的
Just going through the equipment budget
设备预算
to send over to your committee.
没什么不合理的
Nothing unreasonable.
体育馆的一些部分
Some pieces for the gymnasium.
还有五年前的制服
And the five-year-old uniforms
看起来有点破旧
are startin' to look a little ragged.
啊，我们会尽力的
Ah, we'll see what we can do.
委员会下周要开会
Committee's meeting next week.
赢得越多通常意味着校友资助就越多
More wins usually means more money from the alumni.
当然
Sure.
我们的小伙子们怎么样了，教练？
So, how are our boys doing, Coach?
现在说还为时尚早，但很可靠
Early to say, but solid.
哦，他们一直在努力训练
Oh, they've been workin' hard.
我儿子，波，他们整个休赛期
My boy, Bo, had 'em training
－都在训练　－嗯
- all off season. - Hmm.
我认为他们今年会向加州大学发起真正的冲击
Think they're gonna make a real run at Cal this year.
我希望我们能做到
I hope we can.
我们也有一个不错的初级队在训练，你应该...
We got a good junior boat to push 'em, too. You should...
如果可以在我们这挂上横幅，而不是让加州大学
It'd be nice to finally hang a banner up at our place
把它们都拿走，那就太好了
instead of letting Cal have 'em all.
我们会尽力的，先生
We'll do our best, sir.
还有一枚奥运奖牌可以拼一拼
And an Olympic medal to go with it.
波说他们队有机会
Bo says his boat's got a shot.
如果我们加把劲
If we work hard.
并取得一些突破
And catch some breaks.
教练，人生的突破都是赢家自己创造的
Winners make our own breaks in life, Coach.
我们需要这个
And we need this.
机不可失，时不再来
It's now or never.
嗯
Hmm.
如果我们这些影子冒犯了你
If we shadows have offended
那么只需想象，这一切都是梦境
Think but this, and all is mended.
你只是在这里打了个盹...
That you have but slumbered here...
而这些幻象就出现了
While these visions did appear.
谢谢
Thank you.
是一个叫莎士比亚的，对吗？
It's some fella called Shakespeare, right?
你知道，搞音乐的
You know, music people
他们应该收拾好自己的垃圾
should have to take care of their own trash.
比昨晚自助餐厅好多了
Better than the cafeteria last night.
我是说，天哪，我今天差点吃不下饭
I mean, God, I almost couldn't eat today.
你看到那些食物了吗，都被弄成那样了？
You see that old food, all mushed around like that?
你有没有注意到女孩们的桌子下面
You ever notice how under the girls' tables,
总是最糟糕的？
it's always the worst?
你仔细看，女孩们都很邋遢
When you look close, girls are nasty.
你没发现，只是因为她们穿着漂亮的裙子
You don't realize it 'cause of their nice dresses
头发都梳得好好的
and their hair's all fixed up.
但我宁愿清理10个男孩的桌子下面，也不...
But I'll clean under 10 boys' tables before I do one...
哦，唐，还有什么是你不会的吗？
Oh, Don, there anything you can't do?
继续弹啊
Keep goin'.
我们玩得开心吗？
Ain't we got fun?
房租还没付呢，亲爱的
The rent's unpaid, dear
我们没有车
We haven't a car
无论如何，亲爱的
In any way, dear
我们乐天知命
We'll stay as we are
即使我们欠杂货店老板的钱
Even if we owe the grocer
我们玩得开心吗？
Ain't we got fun?
莫里斯在兰茨身后的六号位怎么样？
What about Morris in the six behind Rantz
让亨特在一号位？
and Hunt in the one?
我们上周试过了
We tried that last week.
我不知道
I don't know.
从纸面上看，这应该是可行的
On paper, this should work.
不止是可行
Better than just work.
你让他们和其他100个孩子进行单人比赛
You put them in singles against 100 other kids,
我敢打赌，前8名的选手都在这里
I'd bet on that being the top eight finishers out there.
这就是问题所在
That's the problem.
他们很难记住
They have a hard time remembering
他们不是在参加双桨比赛，尤其是兰茨
they aren't in sculls, especially Rantz.
他们是我在这里见过的
They're a strong a group as I've ever seen
最强大的队伍
come through here
他们可能也是我见过的最糟糕的艇员
and they might also be the worst crew I've ever seen.
这是一个糟糕的组合
It's a bad mix.
是我的错
It's my fault.
也许这些名字并不是问题所在
Well, maybe those names aren't the problem.
有时，年轻的马匹需要一个声音更大的骑师
Sometimes young horses need a louder jockey.
－你想见我，教练？
- You wanted to see me, Coach?
关上门
Close the door.
坐下，鲍比
Sit down, Bobby.
你知道我为什么叫你来吗？
You know why I called you here?
我猜你需要有人帮你打败加州大学
My guess is you need someone to help you beat Cal.
我来给你解释一下
Let me explain something to you.
我给你第二次机会
I'm giving you a second chance.
你要来驾驶初级队的艇
You're gonna drive the JV boat.
－初级队？－没错
- JV? - Yeah, that's right.
现在，听我说
Now, listen to me.
我让你做什么你就得做什么
You're gonna do what I tell you, when I tell you.
如果我看到你还是一意孤行，你就出局了
And if I see you goin' off on your own, then you're out.
这次是永远，你明白吗？
For good this time. You understand?
－明白　－好吧
- Yeah, I do. - All right.
出去吧
Get out.
来吧
Come on!
你的手太高了
Your hands are too high!
解决入水问题
Fix the catch.
同时入水，我们走
One catch, let's go.
像个团队，伙计们
Look like a team, fellas.
蹬腿，抬头
Legs through, eyes up.
蹬腿
Legs through.
你们不同步，跟着休姆
You guys are out of sync. Find Hume.
跟着休姆的节奏
Take it off Hume.
注意桨片高度
Watch those blade heights.
嘿，兰兹，你和我们一起吗？跟着休姆的节奏
Hey, Rantz, you with us? Get with Hume.
蹬腿
Legs through.
蹬腿，来吧
Legs through. Come on!
戴，你入水太高了，低一点
Day, you're catching too high. Lower.
莫里斯，你迟了
Morris, you're late.
够了，停桨，停桨
Enough! Way-nuff! Way-nuff!
是啊，划得不错
Yeah, good ride.
我最喜欢的部分就是，当你们在不同时间入水的时候
And my favorite part is how my nuts vibrated
我的蛋蛋都被震飞起来了
when you guys were all hitting the water at different times.
我们慢得跟屎一样，但感觉很舒服
We were moving slow as shit, but the sensation was nice.
去你的，莫奇
Screw you, Moch.
不，花花公子，你要倒霉了
No, dandy, you're the one screwed.
教练告诉我，如果你们
Coach told me if you guys
不把自己的问题解决了
don't get yourselves figured out,
你不仅要错过下一场比赛
you're not only missing the regatta,
你们今年都不会参加比赛
you're not racing at all this year.
如果什么都不参加
That's a whole hell of a lot of work
那可真是无用功了
to just do nothing with.
那么，想再试一次吗？
So, feel like trying it again?
我准备好了
I'm ready.
很好
That's good.
总是顺着纹路
Always with the grain.
艇员们进展如何？
How's the crew coming along?
比我预想的要难得多
Lot harder than I expected.
这就是练习的目的
Well, that's what practice is for.
开赛前教练会把你们调整好的
Coaches will have you ready for the regatta.
你的家人会来吗？
Your folks gonna make it?
我妈妈在我很小的时候就去世了
My mother, she passed when I was young.
而我爸爸，他几年前就搬走了
And my pop, he had to move off
为了工作
several years ago to find work.
失联了
Kinda lost touch.
谁把你养大的？
Who brought you up?
爸爸觉得我一个人没问题
Pop figured I was okay on my own.
嗯
Hmm.
你当时多大？
How old were you?
差不多14.
Almost 14.
他和我继母
Him and my stepmom,
他们有两个年幼的儿子需要照顾
they had two young boys to care for.
塞奎姆附近没有工作
There was no work around Sequim.
这样对大家都好
Worked out best for everybody.
蹬腿
Legs through.
蹬腿，放松肩膀
Legs through. Soften the shoulders.
抬头
Eyes up.
保持放松
Stay loose.
肩膀放低，乔
Shoulders down, Joe.
放低
Stay low.
放松
Stay loose.
抬头
Eyes up.
好点了吗？
Better?
同步
As one.
把压力给到脚踏板上
Put the pressure in the footplate.
推进
Drive!
她来了，孩子们
Here she is, boys.
也许这是乔治有史以来最出色的杰作
Maybe the finest George has ever made.
现在，这就是你的新家
Now, this is your new home.
好好对待她
Treat her that way.
照顾她，保护她
Care for her. Protect her.
最重要的是，你最好尊重她
Most of all, you better respect her.
好了，穿戴整齐，出发吧
All right, suit up and get out there.
你们一周后要和加州大学比赛
You race against Cal in a week.
不会让你失望的，教练
Won't let you down, Coach.
欢迎来到美丽的华盛顿湖畔
Welcome to a beautiful day at Lake Washington
观看华盛顿哈士奇队
for the annual showdown between the Washington Huskies
和伯克利的加州熊队在太平洋海岸帆船赛上的年度对决
and the Cal Bears of Berkeley in the Pacific Coast Regatta.
和过去30年一样
And just as it has been for the past 30 years,
两英里长的比赛将从沙角开始
the two-mile race will extend from Sand Point
直到谢里登海滩
up to Sheridan Beach.
我们这里聚集了10万名赛艇迷来观看
We have 100,000 race fans gathered here
这肯定是一场自新奥尔良比赛以来
for what is sure to be another maritime battle
我们从未见过的海上战斗
the likes of which we haven't seen since New Orleans.
身穿紫金战袍的华盛顿哈士奇队主教练
And in the purple and gold, Washington Huskies coach,
阿尔・乌尔布里克松将带来一支强大的高级队
Al Ulbrickson, is bringing back a strong senior team
和一艘没有经验的初级艇
and an inexperienced junior boat,
希望扭转上个赛季的糟糕表现
in hopes of reversing a devastating season last year.
毫无疑问，他面临着激烈的竞争
Without a doubt, he's facing stiff competition.
传奇教练凯・埃布莱特再次
Legendary Coach Ky Ebright has once again
带来了两艘强艇
brought two strong boats.
他夸赞他的初级艇员为
He's called his junior crew
可能是他手下最优秀的年轻桨手
possibly the best young oarsmen he has ever had.
加油，华盛顿
Let's go, Washington!
嗨，罗杰
Hi, Roger.
不要想太多做太多，听莫奇的指挥
Don't try and do too much. Listen to Moch.
跟紧点，我们希望加州队会犯错
Stay close, and we'll hope Cal makes a mistake.
身体保持冷静
Stay calm with the body.
举起手来...
Hold your hands up...
－鼓舞人心　－嗯？
- Inspiring. - Hmm?
呃，你没听到我告诉他们
Uh, you missed the part where I told 'em
尽量不要翻船的部分
just to try not to tip over.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
请就座
please take your seats.
距离比赛开始还有五分钟
Five minutes till the start.
嘿，呃，我的孩子们感觉
Hey, uh, my boys are feeling
有点不舒服，艾尔
a little under the weather, Al.
希望你对我们客气点
I hope you take it easy on us.
就算我想相信你也不行，凯
Not even if I believed you, Ky.
两队都已就位
Both teams are in position.
风从北面吹来，时速五英里
Winds are out of the north at five miles an hour.
气温为温和的71华氏度
The temperature is a mild 71 degrees.
好了，大伙，都听到乌尔布里克森说的了
All right, boys. You heard Ulbrickson.
跟近一点，希望他们会犯错
Stick close and hope they make a mistake.
他的意思是别让他难堪
That's his way of saying don't embarrass him
因为他认为你们会让他难堪的
'cause that's what he thinks you're gonna do.
我说都见鬼去吧
I say the hell with all that.
这些人不是来看你们跟近一点的
All these people didn't just come to see you stick close.
我们要让乌尔布里克森看看这艘艇上的都是谁
Let's show Ulbrickson what's in this boat.
准备好了吗？
Ready?
桨手们已经准备就绪
The oarsmen are at the ready.
开始
Row! Row!
他们出发了！
And they're off!
华盛顿队出发很慢
Washington is slow off the block.
早点踩38号!
Step on 'em early! 38!
我们走，很好
Let's go! Good.
我们来了
Yeah, we got 'em.
好吧，给我一个简单明了的28拍
All right. Give me a nice, easy 28.
破，划
In and through.
拉！
And pull!
华盛顿的初级艇
Washington's JV boat
首次参加比赛
is racing for the first time in competition.
加州队轻松突破.，小菜一碟
Cal breaks early. Easy work.
加州队领先华盛顿队有半条艇
Cal has half a boat on Washington.
放松，孩子们，慢慢来
Easy, boys. Nice and easy.
加州队一举取得领先
Cal jumps out to an early lead.
华盛顿队正在努力跟上步伐
Washington is struggling to keep pace.
这就对了，别让他们离开视线
That's right. Just keep them in sight.
别让桨片划空，麦克米伦
Don't sky the blade, McMillin!
破，划
In, through.
肩膀松弛
Shoulders loose.
腿用力
In the legs!
加州队领先华盛顿队整个船身
Cal opening up a full boat on Washington.
在四分之一标志处，加州队已经领先整个船身
And at the quarter mark, it's Cal up a full boat.
来吧，加油，华盛顿
Come on! Come on, Washington!
我们能行，孩子们来吧
We got this, boys! Come on.
划
Through.
破，划
In, through.
别慌，鲍比
Don't panic, Bobby.
不要着急
Don't rush.
加州队仍然没有放缓的迹象
Cal still showing no signs of slowing down.
华盛顿队初尝竞争滋味
Washington is getting its first taste of competition.
乌尔布里克森教练还可以再接再厉
Something Coach Ulbrickson can hope to build on.
划，破，划
Through! In, and through!
推，推
Push! Push!
好了，开始吧，孩子们
All right, here we go, boys.
给我35拍
Give me 35.
让他们看看我们的厉害吧
Let's show 'em what we got.
用力，用力
Build! Build it!
他们在干什么？我说过让加州队走在前面
What are they doing? I said let Cal come back to them.
现在赛程过半
Now at the halfway mark.
哈士奇队突然爆发
The Huskies with a burst.
刚过半程，华盛顿队就开始发力
Just passing the halfway point and Washington is surging.
哦，你最好是对的，莫奇
Oh, you better be right, Moch.
破，划
In, through!
－破，划　－他们来了
- In, through! - Here they come.
华盛顿队来了
Here comes Washington.
抬头
Eyes up.
－抬头　－推
- Eyes up! - Push!
他们已经越过了四分之三标志处
They're past the three-quarter mark.
加州队和华盛顿队齐头并进！
Cal and Washington are neck and neck!
加油，划
Go! Row!
放松！
Stay loose!
推，推
Push! Push!
加州队正在落后
Cal is falling back.
冲
Let's go!
华盛顿正在加快节奏！
Washington is picking up the pace!
华盛顿队超过加州队
Washington's passing Cal!
看看这个
And look at this.
华盛顿队已经取得领先
The Washington boat has taken the lead!
华盛顿队领先半条艇身
Washington by half a boat!
－划！我们走　－来吧
- Row! Let's go! - Come on!
还有200米！
Two hundred meters to go!
－华盛顿领先！　－再划20桨！
- Washington is pulling ahead! - Twenty more strokes!
加油，加油
Come on, come on.
加油，上
Come on! Go!
华盛顿队领先了整条船身
Washington by a full boat!
破，划！100米！
In and through! One hundred meters!
还有15桨！
Fifteen more!
加油，加油
Come on! Come on!
蹬！还有10桨
Through! Ten more!
50米！
Fifty meters!
50米
华盛顿队要赢了！
Washington is going to do it!
你们能行！破，划
You got this! In and through!
推！
Push!
25米！
Twenty-five meters!
那就是终点
And there's the flag!
华盛顿队做到了！
Washington has done it!
华盛顿队初级艇赢得了他们的首场比赛！
Washington's junior boat has won their first competition!
耶
Yeah!
对于这些年轻人来说，这是一个多么有希望的开始！
What a promising start for these young men!
天啊
Jesus!
我这比赛道记录快了9秒
I got nine seconds under the course record.
一样
Same.
最后三分之一的速度比一开始还要快
And the final third is faster than the first.
到底是从哪里来的力气？
Where the hell did that come from?
我猜那个小矮子知道自己在做什么
I guess that little runt knew what he was doin'.
－好哦　－好哦
- Yeah! - Yeah!
干的漂亮，孩子们
It's all you, boys!
你们都是
All you!
漂亮
Yeah!
一
One!
二
Two!
三
Three!
我喜欢你的帽子，谢谢
I like your hat. Thank you. Thank you.
来吧
Come on!
华盛顿
Washington!
来吧
Come on!
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
你好
Hi.
我可以习惯这样
I could get used to this.
第一次获胜的感觉如何？
How did your first win feel?
好极了
Great.
下一次会更快
Next one's gonna be even faster.
你怎么划得这么快？
How did you go so fast?
哦，我们就是拼命在划
Oh, we just rowed as quick as we could.
虽然你很强壮，但这一定很难
It must have been hard, even though you're strong.
你累吗？
You get tired?
是啊，是啊，是挺艰难的
Yeah, yeah, it was pretty rough.
太累了，不想去安静的地方
Too tired to go someplace quiet
告诉我你是如何做到的吗？
and show me how you did it?
哦，当然不会
Oh, hell no.
你知道，让莫里斯吐在我背上
You know, this might make all the times
那么多次，可能也都值了
Morris puked on my back worth it.
我今天收到了这个
I got this today.
是一个西装革履的家伙给我的
Some fellow in a suit just gave it to me.
他说我们赢了让他很高兴，他想让我...
Said us winning made him so happy, he wanted me to have...
我们都让他很开心，戈多
Shoot, we all made him happy, Gordo.
我代数课上的孩子
Kid in my algebra class
主动要帮我做作业
offered to do my homework for me.
－我就让他做了　－应该的
- I let the sap do it. - You should.
我们继续赢下去
We keep on winnin',
可能真的会在这里实现的
we're gonna have it made in this place.
－你今天干得真不错　－嗯？
- You did so good today. - Huh?
我说你今天...
I said you did so...
我说你今天表现得很好
I said you did so good today.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是...很有趣
It was... It was fun.
什么？
What?
过来，我说这很有趣
Come here. I said it was fun.
你想去个安静的地方吗？
Do you wanna go someplace quiet?
你在干什么？
Watcha doin'?
我就看看
I'm watching.
你为什么不跟任何人说话？
Why aren't you talking to anybody?
我不太爱说话
I'm not much of a talker.
啊
Ah.
嘿，看那边
Hey, look over there.
看到那个戴眼镜的豆芽菜了吗？
You see that beanpole in the glasses?
是啊
Yeah.
他在学拉丁语
He's studying Latin.
－哦　－拉丁语
- Oh. - Latin.
你不必说太多
You don't have to say much.
听着，休谟
Listen, Hume.
今晚，不是明晚，也不是下周
Tonight, not tomorrow night, or next week.
今晚是你最好的机会
Tonight is your best shot.
你继续，我想我没事
You go on. I think I'm okay.
看在上帝的份上
Christ sake.
嘿，听好了
Hey, listen up!
我们中间有一位音乐家
We got a musician in our midst.
稍加鼓励
With a little encouragement,
可能会让他给我们带来一些现场音乐
we might just get him to give us some live music.
唐・休姆
Don Hume!
快上来，快上来
Get up here. Get up here.
来吧，唐！
Come on, Don!
不，不
No. No.
－嘿，小心点　－不，不，不
- Hey, watch out. - No, no, no, no, no.
鲍比，拿凳子来
Bobby, get the stool.
钢琴师
The piano man.
约翰，约翰，约翰
John, John, John
－不，不，不　－到了
- No, no, no. - There we go.
一切准备就绪，大师.
All ready for you there, maestro.
让我们为唐鼓掌！
Let's hear it for Don!
唐・休姆
Don Hume.
来吧，唐！
Come on, Don!
我们知道你能做到
We know you can do it.
－来吧，唐　－加油，唐尼
- Come on, Don. - Come on, Donnie.
我觉得我不应该在这
I don't think that I should be here.
他不能进来
He can't be in here.
闭嘴，卡洛琳
Oh, shut up, Carolyn.
上周我看见你在窗前抽烟
I saw you smoking at your window last week.
那边太吵了
It was too loud in there.
对，大家很快乐，他们玩得很开心
Yeah. People are happy. They're having fun.
对，因为你
Yeah, because of you.
好吧，我要换衣服了
Okay, I'm changing.
眼睛看着墙壁
Eyes on the wall.
好
Right.
你知道自己会赢吗？
Did you know you were gonna win?
不，我的手臂在颤抖
No. My arms, they were shaking.
我太紧张了
I was so nervous.
我们都在大声尖叫
We were all screaming so loud.
广播说这是有史以来最快的一次
The radio said it was the fastest ever.
对，教练是这么告诉我们的
Yeah, that's what Coach told us.
我打赌你们每场都能赢
I bet you win every race.
只要不自命不凡就好
Just don't get all stuck-up and everything.
我把它留着，以防再遇到你
I just kept that in case I ever ran into you again.
不得不...
And had to, um...
证明你暗恋过我，就像我说的那样
prove that you had that crush on me, like I said.
西姆达斯小姐，开门
Miss Simdars, open this door.
你...你该走了
You... You should go.
你该走了，你必须走了，你必须走了
You should go. You need to go. You need to go.
西姆达斯小姐，马上开门，小姐
Miss Simdars, open this door right now, young lady.
如果里面有男性访客
If you have a male visitor in there,
那么，你知道后果是什么
well, you know the consequences.
一分钟
One minute!
－什么　－太高了吗？
- What? - Is that too far?
－不　－那很好
- No. - You're fine.
西姆达斯小姐
Miss Simdars!
我们玩得开心吗？
Ain't we got fun?
收税员越来越近了
Tax collector's getting closer
尽管如此，我们还是很开心
Still, we got fun
没有比这更确定的了
There's nothing surer
富者愈富，穷者愈穷
The rich get rich and the poor get poorer
同时，此时
In the meantime, in between time
我们玩得开心吗？
Ain't we got fun?
干得好
Well done!
好，好
Okay! Yeah!
唐・休姆，女士们先生们
Don Hume, ladies and gentlemen.
－哈佛，耶鲁？－嗯
- Harvard, Yale? - Mm-hmm.
两队的成绩都是我们无法企及的
Both have put up times we haven't gotten close to.
通常就是这样
That's how it usually goes.
东部的孩子在会穿鞋之前就已经上艇了
Kids back East are in boats before they're in shoes.
学校有更多的人才可供选择
Schools just have more talent to choose from.
这就是钱能给你买到的
That's what money buys you.
我们需要点优势，汤姆
We need an edge, Tom.
划，破，划
Through. In and through.
破，划
In and through.
划
And through!
抬头
Eyes up!
破，划
In and through!
抬高
Stand tall.
蹬腿
Legs through.
破，划
In and through.
蹬腿
Legs through.
破，划
In, through.
In and through.
蹬腿
Legs through.
停桨
Way-nuff!
其他人都累了，他们却越战越勇
Everybody else tires and they just get stronger.
这是他们第三次击败校队
That's the third time they beat the varsity squad.
也许下次就输了
Maybe next time.
我只是觉得风险太大了
I just think it's too big of a risk.
波基普西今年不仅仅是冠军赛
Poughkeepsie is more than just the championship this year.
也是奥运会选拔赛
It's for the Olympics.
我知道比赛意味着什么，汤姆
I know what the race means, Tom.
在大型比赛中，经验很重要
Experience counts for something in big races.
校队有一半人
Half those guys on varsity
去年在波基普西参加过比赛
competed at Poughkeepsie last year.
－他们输了　－他们今年更好
- And they lost. - They're better this year.
如果不知道他们的年龄
If you didn't know their ages,
不知道他们划了多久
you didn't know how long they've been rowing,
假设你第一次看到这两艘艇...
you're looking at both boats for the first time...
后院的计时赛不算
A time trial in the backyard does not count.
这和正规赛场是两码事
That is not the same thing as a race.
看看比赛时间
Look at the competition times.
没那么容易
It's not that easy.
拜托，你知道的
Come on, you know that.
是的，是的
Yes. Yes.
是的，我知道
Yes, I know.
你表现得就像校队是群废物一样
You're acting like the varsity boat is scrappin'.
要知道，那艘艇也没有输过比赛
You know that boat hasn't lost a race either.
就在不久前
And it wasn't that long ago
你还在期待初级队
you were just hopin' the JV boat
能在不沉没的情况下坚持到终点
was gonna make it to the finish line without sinking.
现在，艾尔
Now, Al,
现在你却说要把我们所有的筹码都押在他们身上
now you're talkin' about putting all our chips on 'em.
你认为校队能在柏林拿奖吗？
Do you think varsity could medal in Berlin?
我们不是在谈论奖牌
We're not talkin' about a medal.
我们说的是去那里的机会
We're talkin' about a shot at gettin' there.
就算他们到了那？
If they got there?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们今年需要一场胜利，艾尔
We need a win this year, Al.
给我们付钱的人，他们需要一场胜利
The people who pay us, they need a win.
你派一艇孩子过去
You send a boat full of kids down there
他们就会被绊倒
and they trip up,
你就等着
you're sticking your neck way out there.
引颈就戮吧，我也是
Makes it a real easy target. And mine, too.
我需要这份工作
I need this job.
你怎么看，乔治？
What do you think, George?
嗯
Hmm.
你在艇上那会
When you were in a boat,
你的划艇技术这里无人能及
you rowed like no one else that's ever come through here.
我记得我看着你
I remember watching you,
真想知道我的船到底能跑多快
wondering how fast one of my shells could go
如果里面有8个和你一样的人
if there were eight just like you in it.
那群孩子
That bunch of kids
可能是最接近我这想法的了
might be as close to that as I'll ever get.
如果我把他们派出去，他们还没准备好呢？
And if I send them out there and they aren't ready?
那就像汤姆说的那样
Then it's like Tom said.
斧头很可能会落下
The axe will likely fall,
砍得脖子疼
and fall hard.
现在你的口气开始像我妻子了
Now you're starting to sound like my wife.
海泽尔是个聪明的女人
Well, Hazel's a smart woman.
我就当你在夸我
I'll take that as a compliment.
大家早上好
Good morning, everybody.
谢谢
Thank you.
众所周知，波基普西帆艇赛
Now, as we all know, uh, the Poughkeepsie Regatta
一直是本赛季最重要的比赛
is always the most important race of the season.
今年，它的意义更加重大
This year, there's even more riding on it,
因为获胜者将获得奥运会的参赛资格
because the winner will qualify for an Olympic spot.
好
Yes!
它也是华盛顿大学已近20年
It's also a race that the University of Washington
未尝胜绩的一个赛事
has not won in almost two decades,
但是...
but... but...
我们今年有一艘艇
we have a boat this year
我相信他们可以改变这一切
that I believe could change all that.
这艘艇不仅能在波基普西夺冠
A boat that could not only win at Poughkeepsie,
而且
but
有足够的实力在柏林一展身手
is strong enough to have a real shot in Berlin.
还有...
And, uh...
那艘艇就是我们的初级艇
that boat is our junior boat.
是的，你们都听到了
Yeah, you heard me.
听着，我知道这不合常理
Listen, I understand that that's unorthodox.
－不合常理？简直是疯了　－我正在尽我所能...
- Unorthodox? It's insane. - I'm doing everything I can...
你不能这么做
You can't do that.
我们团队和华盛顿大学的
in the best interests of our team
最佳利益
and the University of Washington.
谢谢
Thank you.
这简直是胡扯！
This is bullshit!
你疯了吗？
Have you lost your mind?
那些花了四年时间
What about those boys who spent
在这上面的孩子怎么办？
the last four years working for this?
我的工作就是派最好的艇去参赛，本
My job is to put the best boat in the water, Ben.
你的工作？我付的钱
Your job? I pay for your job.
没有我支持，你认为
Without the boosters, where do you think
你们买艇的钱是从哪里来的？
the money for your boats comes from, huh?
你那该死的薪水哪里来
For your goddamn salary?
让我做我的工作怎么样？
How about you let me do my job?
让我们安定下来
Let's just settle down
冷静地谈谈，来吧
and talk about this calmly. Come on.
没什么好谈的，杰伊
There's nothin' to talk about, Jay.
我的团队，我做主
My team, my decision.
那就不再是你的团队了
Then it's not your team anymore.
我会让你屁股挪窝
I'll make sure your ass is fired
在火车开往波基普西之前
before the train leaves for Poughkeepsie.
－本，我们不会搞到...　－好吧
- Ben, we're not gonna get... - All right.
博勒斯和你一样能干
Bolles is just as capable as you.
甚至更好
Better even.
我会和艾尔一样选择
I'd do the same as Al.
我希望你知道自己在做什么
I hope you know what you're doing.
本
Ben!
我知道吗？
Do I?
你当然知道
Sure you do.
真不敢相信你要去参加奥运会
I can't believe you're going to the Olympics.
我们得先打败其他学校
We gotta beat those other schools first,
但教练说，我们的机会和其他队一样多
but Coach says we have as good a shot as anybody.
你不准和那些纽约女孩调情
You can't flirt with any of those New York girls.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
马上回来
Be back in a second.
乔？
Joe?
在报纸上看到你的照片了
Saw your picture in the paper.
小哈利把它剪了下来
Harry Junior clipped it out.
你们什么时候从加州回来的？
When did you get back from California?
好几年了
Couple of years.
那里的情况也没好到哪里去
You know, things weren't much better down there.
这么说，你一直都在这里？
So, you've been here all that time?
就在前面一点点远
Down the road a bit.
你打算告诉我吗？
Were you ever gonna tell me?
你做得很好
You're doin' all right.
你离开的时候，我才14岁
I was 14 when you left.
我在那个年纪就上战场了
I went to war when I was that age.
那么，你在想什么，乔？
So, what do you wanna do, Joe?
啊？
Huh?
想搬回家吗？
Move home?
我是说，我需要人帮忙
I mean, I could use the help.
这样吧，我每天付你一美元
Tell you what, I'll pay you a dollar a day
如果你还记得如何砍树的话
if you still remember how to cut a tree.
或者，你宁愿继续划你的艇
Or maybe you'd rather just keep rowing your boat.
你不欠我什么，乔
You don't owe me a thing, Joe.
我也不欠你的
I don't owe you.
你做得很好
You're doing just fine.
我会转达问候的
I'll pass on regards.
对不起
I'm sorry.
这结果是最好的
Works out for the best.
是的，但这并不意味着就没事了
Yeah, but that doesn't make it okay.
也许吧
Maybe.
我得走了
I gotta go.
你应该来睡一觉
You should come get some sleep
在太阳升起之前
before the sun rises over that.
我很快就过去
I'll be in there soon.
我真喜欢这样的景色
I sure love that view.
我知道
I know.
我只是希望我能像以前那样享受它
I just wish I could enjoy it the way I used to.
为什么不能
Why don't you
要来看看有没有其他风景可以欣赏吗？
come see if there's another view you can enjoy?
好吧
Okay.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们会成为世界上最快的艇员
We're gonna be the fastest crew the world has ever seen.
把冠军带回家，艾尔
Bring home the championship, Al!
－还有一枚金牌　－我们会努力的
- And a gold medal! - We'll try.
哦，天哪
Oh, boy.
我们可能想赢得比赛，对吧？
We might wanna try and win this thing, huh?
没有压力
No pressure.
－祝你们好运　－把奖牌带回家，孩子们
- Good luck! - Bring it home, boys!
我会通过收音机收听
I'll be listening on the radio.
如果他们采访你，跟我问个好
Say hello if they interview you.
现在也许是个好机会
This might be a good time to tell you
告诉你我爱上你了，乔
that I'm in love with you, Joe.
好，我得走了
All right. I gotta go.
嘿！
Hey! Hey!
是的，她看着我
Yeah, she looked at me.
兰茨
Rantz!
我破产了，谁给我一便士
I'm busted. Someone give me a penny.
幸运，我会让你看看的
Lucky, I'll let you watch.
嘿，乔，把你的夹克给我
Hey, Joe, give me your jacket.
这样我有一半押注的钱了
That'll get me halfway to ante.
乔，别走
Joe, stick around.
嘿，别走啊，流浪汉乔
Hey, don't run away, Hobo Joe.
他开玩笑的
He's playin'.
他开玩笑的，他开玩笑的
He's playin'. He's playin'.
他开玩笑的
He's playin'.
－天啊，查克　－开个玩笑而已
- Jesus, Chuck. - Was just jokin'.
好吧，你的笑话太烂了
Yeah, well, your jokes are lousy.
我没有别的意思
I didn't mean anything by it.
事实是，我老爸几年前就破产了，所以...
Truth is, my old man went bust years ago, so...
我穿的新衣服，都是从伍尔沃斯超市顺来的
Any new clothes I wear, I swipe from Woolworth's.
无所谓
Doesn't matter.
我只是说，我们并没有什么不同
Just sayin' we're not different.
你和我
You and me.
只不过你不是小偷
Except you're not a thief.
一，停桨
One! Way-nuff!
放下
Drop it.
再来一次！节奏再快一点
Again! Need to get sharper.
来吧
Come on.
你们不同步，跟着休姆
You guys are out of sync. Find Hume.
跟着休姆的节奏
Take it off Hume.
像个团队，伙计们
Look like a team, fellas.
同步
As one.
你们不同步
You're out of sync.
好吧，不，停桨
Okay, no, no. Way-nuff.
我们要去哪里？嘿，乔，你和我们在一起吗？
Where are we off? Hey, Joe, you with us?
－我　－对，锁定唐的节奏
- Me? - Yeah, lock in on Don.
你在说什么？我不是问题所在
What are you talkin' about? I'm not the problem.
再来一次
Go again.
来吧
Come on.
破，划
In and through.
好吧，再来三桨，三
All right, give me three more. Three,
二
two,
一，停桨
one. Way-nuff!
这样我们肯定能拿到第六名
That'd get us a solid sixth.
这是新水域，他们还没适应
It's new water, they're still getting comfortable.
第一轮还比较快
First times were faster.
他们越来越不协调了
They're getting less comfortable.
怎么回事？
What is the matter?
还没协调好，我会带好他们的，教练
Not in tune yet. I'll get 'em there, Coach.
让我们在赛前先协调好吧，鲍比
Let's do it before the race, Bobby.
再来一次
Go again.
好了，伙计们，左舷，退后
All right, fellas. Port side, back it down.
右舷，打开，准备好了吗？
Starboard, tap on. Ready?
可能是紧张
Probably nervous.
他们只是孩子，艾尔
They're just kids, Al.
这就是为什么大家都告诉我
That's why everybody told me
我不该带他们来
I was wrong for bringin' them.
我没有本钱再让他们孩子气下去了
I just can't afford for them to be kids.
现在不一样了
Not anymore.
－看起来他们...　－我知道问题在哪了
- It looks like they... - I know what's wrong.
带进来
Bring it in.
你们完美地划了500米
You have 500 perfect meters.
然后另外500米，看起来就像
And then another five, where it looks like
你们在划8条不同的艇
you're rowing eight different boats.
时间就是有点对不上
The timing's just a little off.
乔，你的心思在哪里呢，孩子？
Joe, where is your head at, son?
－在艇上　－不，不在
- It's in the boat. - No, it's not.
你在跟着自己的节奏走
You're setting your own pace.
你的入水高于其他人
Your catch is higher than the rest.
－我想...　－别打断我
- I'm trying to... - Don't interrupt me.
你就像在单人划艇一样
You're rowing like you're in a single.
我们已经训练太久了，不可能忘记
We've been doing this too goddamn long to forget
你是在一个8人艇上
you're in an eight-man shell.
现在，你想在艇上吗？
Now, do you wanna be in the boat
还是我让别人来坐你的位子？
or am I'm gonna put someone else in your seat?
我不在乎
I don't care.
科伊
Coy!
你坐在兰茨的位置上
You're in Rantz's seat.
滚出去，你不在乎？滚出去
Get out. You don't care? Get out.
科伊，来吧，我们走
Coy, come on, let's go.
看来你明天要参加比赛了
Looks like you're racin' tomorrow.
现在，也许我们可以像一个团队一样划了
Now, maybe we can row as a team.
去和教练谈谈，告诉他你想回去
And just go talk to Coach, tell him you want back in.
我不会求他把我的位置还给我的
I'm not beggin' him to give my place back.
－我受够了　－你要去哪儿？
- I'm done with that. - Where you gonna go?
你的钱又不够买张火车票
Ain't like you got money enough for a train ticket.
我会想办法的，我一向如此
I'll figure somethin' out. I always have.
你要在波基普西找个车住进去吗？
Are you gonna live in a car in Poughkeepsie?
你好，罗杰，你好，乔
Hello, Roger. Hello, Joe.
我需要在“赫斯基快艇”上再涂一层漆
I need to put another coat on the Husky Clipper.
需要人帮忙
I could use a hand.
我爷爷会让我帮他造的船上油
My grandfather would let me help oil the shells he built.
大多数人讨厌它是因为有味道
Most hate it because of the smell.
我一闻到鲸油的味道，立刻就听到了他的声音
I catch the scent of whale oil and immediately hear his voice
告诉我“继续涂”
telling me to, "Keep putting it on"
直到你能从反光中看到你脸上的雀斑
until you can see your freckles in the reflection.
这样我才知道它又好又滑
That's how I'd know it was good and slick.
这样，它就能像刀刃一样划过水面
So it would cut through the water like a knife blade.
划得再快也没用
How it didn't matter how fast someone rowed
如果水不是以完全正确的方式
if the water didn't flow across the hull
流过船体
in the exact right way.
如果重量没有恰到好处地平衡
If the weight wasn't balanced just right.
每一部分都要相互配合
Every piece working with the other.
艇员也是一样
It's the same with the crew.
以至于两者之间真的没有什么区别
So much that there's really no difference between the two.
他们因一起度过的所有时光而团结在一起
They're connected by all the hours spent together.
汗水和痛苦
Sweat and pain
洇湿了艇身的纹理，它们变成了在水面上穿梭的
bleeds into the grain as they become one magical thing
一个神奇的东西
that moves across the water
就像天生就不属于任何地方一样
like it was born to be nowhere else.
我造过很多好船，但最好的艇
I've built a lot of good boats, but the best ones,
每一个部件都完全吻合的艇
the boats where every part fits exactly as it should,
每一个人都信任他身后的人的艇
where every man trusts the one behind him,
才是人们永远铭记的艇
they are the boats people remember forever.
这就是这艘艇可能成为的样子
That's what this boat could be.
看看这艘所有部件都完美配合的艇能跑多快
Be a shame for anyone to miss
如果有人错过了，那就太可惜了
seeing how fast it could go with all the right pieces.
乔，你爸爸放弃了你，他放弃了你
Joe, your dad gave up on you. He quit on you.
你就只会放弃
All you know is quitting.
但在我看来，你不是他
But it seems to me you're not him.
或者你是？
Or are you?
－是的　－是的，非常好
- Yes. - Yes, it's very nice.
如果你们两个能站在一起的话
If I can get you two to just stand together.
再来一张，完美
Just for one. And perfect.
我们那边见
I'll, uh, see you over there.
我能为你做什么，乔？
What can I do for you, Joe?
我想要回我的位置
I want my seat back.
为什么？
Why?
我在里面度过的那些时光
All that time I spent in it,
我们一起付出的努力
the work we all did together...
那艘艇...
That boat...
是我的全部
it's all I got.
伙计们和...
The boys and...
我只有这些了
It's all I got.
我不能失去
I can't lose that.
我对你们说的第一件事就是
You know, one of the first things I said to you boys was
如果你的身体承受不了，这并不丢人
there's no shame if your body can't hold up to this.
精神也是一样
The same goes for the mind.
听着，我知道要信任那条艇上的每一个人
Listen, I know it isn't easy to trust every other person
就像信任自己一样，并不容易
on that boat as much as you trust yourself.
但这与你无关
But it's not about you.
虽然你很优秀，但这不是你一个人的事情，乔
As good as you are, it's not about you, Joe,
或者我，或其他任何一个人
or me, or anybody else.
这是关于艇的
It's about the boat.
是的，先生
Yes, sir.
这是我想去的地方
It's where I wanna be.
好的
Okay.
你最好穿上队服
Well, you better get dressed.
谢谢
Thank you.
真的，谢谢你
Really, thank you.
今天的帆艇赛
Today's regatta
它既是一场比赛，也是一场社会实验
is as much a social experiment as it is a race.
一场富有精英
A clash of character.
和平头百姓的角色冲突
Of old money versus no money at all.
六艘生活之艇对上一艘生存之艇
Six boats of want-to's against one filled with have-to's.
这九个工人阶级男孩从美国西部来到这里
These nine working-class boys arrived from the American West
肩负着一个国家的重任，这个国家从他们
on the shoulders of a country that sees itself
坚定的年轻面孔中看到了自己
in their determined young faces.
看到他们的奋斗，勇气和精神
Sees their struggles, their grit, their spirit.
他们将“赫斯基快艇号”视作自身
And they've claimed the Husky Clipper as their own.
因为艇上都是弱者
Because it's a boat full of underdogs
代表一个弱势民族
representing an underdog nation.
一个被打倒
A nation of people who have been beaten down
但拒绝离开的民族
but refuse to go away.
拒绝停止努力工作，因为他们只知道努力工作
Refuse to stop working hard, 'cause that's all they know.
只会努力工作
All they have ever done.
所以，找好你的位置，在河边或收音机旁
So, find your place, by the river or the radio.
今天，我们要为勇气、心智和体力喝彩
And cheer for guts and heart and brawn
战胜特权和名望，冲向终点
to beat privilege and prestige to the finish line today.
为来自华盛顿的小伙子们欢呼
Cheer for the boys from Washington.
听好了，我们在第七道
Listen up. We're in lane seven.
海军和加州大学想一举领先
Navy and Cal are gonna wanna jump to a lead.
就让他们去
We just let 'em.
就是这样，孩子们
This is it, boys.
不错的强势开局
Nice, strong start.
我们要保持42拍的速度，对吧？
We're gonna keep a 42 count coming out, right?
加利福尼亚队会很拼命的，好吗？
California's gonna go out hard, okay?
你们必须咬死他们
You gotta stick with them.
只要你们在两个长度范围以内
As long as you're within two lengths,
－就保持在30拍　－你的肩膀怎么样了？
- stay under a 30 stroke. - How's your shoulder?
－你还好吗？－我很好
- Are you okay? - I'm good.
我想看到你们坚持到底，战胜痛苦
I wanna see you push yourself through that pain.
然后在中点换成35拍
Then go to a 35 at the halfway mark.
你要放慢速度，慢慢进入平稳的34拍
You're gonna slow down and ease into a nice, steady 34.
继续前进，继续推进
Keep going, keep pushing.
坚持到底
Keep pushing all the way through.
前面的所有艇只都会开始疲劳
All the boats out in front will start to tire
而你才刚刚开始发力
and you'll just be getting started.
都知道计划了
You know the plan.
我们会把一些精力留到最后
We'll save something for the end.
划艇四英里对你们来说不算什么
Four miles in a boat should be nothing to you.
这是你们的比赛，好吗？
This is your race, all right?
这是我们的表演时间
This is our time.
我们知道自己在做什么，我们以前来过这里
We know what we're doin'. We've been here before, boys.
现在最好去那边，展示一下我们的实力
Now better get out there and show 'em what I already know.
波基普西帆艇赛
The Poughkeepsie Regatta.
今天的帆艇赛是美国最大的
Today's regatta is the greatest
单日赛艇比赛
one-day rowing event in America.
－注意脚下　－像凯・埃布莱特这样的教练
- Watch your step. - Coaches like Ky Ebright,
罗斯特・卡洛和阿尔・乌尔布里克松
Rusty Callow and Al Ulbrickson
不仅希望获胜
are not only hoping for a win,
也想获得去柏林参赛的机会
but a chance to compete in Berlin.
赛艇爱好者们登上观景台
As rowing fans board observation cars
挤满哈德逊河岸
and crowd the shores of the Hudson River,
七艘赛艇在起跑线上已就位
seven shells take their places at the starting line.
锡拉丘兹大学，海军
Syracuse, Navy,
康奈尔大学和哥伦比亚大学
Cornell, and Columbia,
宾夕法尼亚大学，加州大学和华盛顿大学在为
Penn, Cal, and Washington ready themselves
可能是他们年轻的生命中
for what could be the most important race
最重要的比赛做准备
of their young lives.
一个参加奥运会的机会
A chance to compete in the Olympics.
我们走吧
Let's go.
－祝你好运，杰克　－你也是
- Good luck, Jack. - You, too.
发令枪已举起
The starting gun is up.
桨在前方已就位
Oars to frontstops.
近10万名观众屏住呼吸，翘首以盼
Nearly 100,000 spectators hold their breath in anticipation.
克鲁姆埃尔伯水面一片寂静
A hush falling over Crum Elbow.
－划！开始了
- Row! And here we go.
华盛顿哈士奇队正在划艇
Washington Huskies are now rowing
对抗加州大学的学长们
against the seniors of Cal.
“哈士奇”是比赛中唯一的初级艇
Huskies are the only junior boat in the competition.
给我一个简单明了的28拍
Give me a nice, easy 28.
跟着唐的节拍
Fall in with Don.
破，划
In and through.
这七支训练有素的艇员队伍
These seven finely trained crews
正在搅动上哈德逊河的水域
are churning the waters of the Upper Hudson
在一场力量、速度和协调性的
in a supreme rowing test
的最高测试中
of power, speed and coordination.
保持节拍，鲍比
Hold that pace, Bobby.
在第一阶段，加利福尼亚州，宾夕法尼亚州
And at the quarter mark, we have California, Penn
和海军冲在前面
and Navy out in front
领先其他队半条艇位
with a half-boat lead on the rest of the field.
好了，你们划得节奏非常好
All right, your stroke rate is perfect.
节约能量
Save your power.
让他们累去
Let 'em get tired.
损耗他们
Wear 'em down.
华盛顿正在跌到最后一名
Washington is falling back to last place.
落后领先者四个艇长
Four lengths behind the leaders.
现在，鲍比
Now, Bobby.
节约
Save!
节约能量
Save power.
损耗他们
Wear 'em down.
－他在干什么？－不能再等了
- What's he doing? - It has to be now.
来吧，孩子们
Come on, boys.
等着
Wait for it.
好了，唐，给我36拍，开始
All right, Don, give me 36. Go!
蹬腿
Legs through.
他们来了
And here they come.
看看新手
Looking for freshwater,
鲍比・莫奇正在赶上锡拉丘兹队
Bobby Moch is steering right into Syracuse's lane.
破，划，我们走
In and through. Let's go.
抬腿
Legs up.
戳！戳！
Jab! Jab!
放过我们
Get off us!
嘿，去死吧，锡拉库扎！
Hey, go to hell, Syracuse!
那是什么鬼？
What the hell is that?
华盛顿正在超越锡拉丘兹大学
Washington is passing Syracuse.
他们身后还有一英里半的距离
And with a mile and a half behind them,
各队七零八落
teams are falling away
但加州大学队和海军队无人能望其项背
but no one is gaining on California and Navy.
好样的
Attaboy.
摇，摇
Row! Row!
保持四个艇长的领先优势
Holding a four-length lead,
加州大学和海军正在进行双艇竞赛
Cal and Navy are in a two-boat race.
好吧，给我10个大的给乌尔布里克森看看，冲
All right, give me 10 big ones for Ulbrickson. Go!
华盛顿加快了步伐
Washington has picked up the pace.
鲍比・莫奇终于让他的队员冲进了比赛
Bobby Moch finally getting his crew in this race.
哈士奇队横扫康奈尔队
The Huskies sweeping by Cornell.
追向宾夕法尼亚州立大学和哥伦比亚大学
Headed for Penn and Columbia.
海军和加州大学仍然领先四个身位
Navy and Cal still ahead by four lengths.
好吧，给我40拍
All right! Give me 40!
上啊
Let's go!
破，划
In, through!
华盛顿正在迅速超越哥伦比亚雄狮
Washington is quickly gaining on Columbia's Lions.
最好还不算太晚
Better not be too late.
赫斯基快艇超过了哥伦比亚...
The Husky Clipper bustles by Columbia...
－来吧　-上升到了第三位
- Come on!  - ...and into third place!
来吧
Come on!
推，展
Push! Extend!
现在，再来10桨
Now, give me 10 more
为了波克
for Pocock!
还剩400米，华盛顿赶上来了
With 400 meters to go, here comes Washington!
破，划
In and through!
In, through!
破，划
－划！－再来20桨
- Through! - Twenty more strokes!
19！
Nineteen!
华盛顿来到了第二位
Washington has taken second place!
他们还有足够的时间追上加州大学队吗？
Do they have enough left to catch Cal?
蹬腿
Legs through!
－来吧，孩子们　－来吧
- Come on, boys. - Come on.
你们能行的，孩子们
You got this, boys.
看看华盛顿吧！
Look at Washington!
真不敢相信我所看到的
I don't believe what I'm seeing.
哈士奇队能做到吗？他们能做到吗？
Can the Huskies do it? Can they do it?
来10个大的
Give me 10 big ones
给所有不相信你的人！
for all the people who didn't believe in you!
冲
Go!
给我拿下加州队！
Give me Cal!
拿下加州队
I want Cal!
对，我们要赢了，喔
Yeah, we're workin'! Whoo!
他们正在前进
They're making their move!
孩子们，加油
Boys, come on.
蹬腿！
Legs through!
还剩200米
With 200 meters left,
华盛顿正在超越加州
Washington is passing Cal!
破，划
In, through!
抬头
Eyes up!
还有100米，华盛顿就要赢了！
With 100 meters to go, Washington is going to do it!
华盛顿要赢了
Washington is going to do it!
划，破，划
Through! In and through!
－抬头，破　－来吧
- Eyes up! In! - Come on.
华盛顿赢得了比赛，各位！
Washington has won the race, folks!
华盛顿赢得了比赛！
Washington has won the race!
华盛顿赢了！
Washington has won!
多么精彩的比赛
What a race!
教练乌尔布里克森的豪赌得到了回报
Coach Ulbrickson's big gamble has paid off,
女士们，先生们
ladies and gentlemen.
华盛顿哈士奇队
The Washington Huskies
要去柏林争夺金牌了
are going to Berlin to compete for gold.
－真是一场精彩的比赛　－是的！
- What a race indeed! - Yes!
哦...
Oh...
我真的很喜欢你的笑容
I do love your smile.
你应该经常笑一笑
You should do it more often.
我们成功了，孩子们！
We did it, boys!
我觉得你是想让我们都得心脏病
I think that you were trying to give us all a heart attack.
不到万不得已，我不想打破他们的节奏
I just didn't want to break their rhythm till I had to.
我真的不知道
I honest to God didn't know
全世界有这么多的虾
there were this many shrimp in the entire world.
您是否介意与我们的听众分享一下
Do you mind sharing with our listeners,
在艇上的感觉如何
what was the feeling in the boat
在你们落后四个艇位的时候？
when you were four lengths back?
有没有恐慌？
Was there any panic?
没有恐慌
Uh, there was no panic.
我们所有人
All of us,
我们都知道我们可以在需要的时候到位
we knew we could make up the ground when we needed to.
如果可以的话
And, if I could,
我能跟我的乔伊斯打个招呼吗？
could I say hello to my girl Joyce back home?
等我回来就让你戴上金牌
I'll let you wear the gold medal when I get back.
没错，各位
That's right, folks.
他们将把金牌带回家
They'll be bringing the gold medal home
为了我们所有华盛顿人
for all of us back in Washington.
哦
Oh.
这太棒了
This is great.
你们是什么时候知道的？
So, you guys all knew about it when?
我今晚才听到？
And I'm hearing about it tonight?
你知道这听起来像什么吗？
You know what this sounds like to me?
听起来你们好像在改变规则
It sounds like you guys are changing the rules
因为你想从我们这里偷走这个
because you're trying to steal this from us.
没有人想偷什么，乌尔布里克森教练
No one is trying to steal anything, Coach Ulbrickson.
我只是和你谈谈
I'm just speaking to you
以美国赛艇奥林匹克主席的身份
as the U.S. Rowing Olympic Chairman
告诉你这个事实
and telling you the facts.
美国赛艇协会没有钱
U.S. Rowing does not have the money
来资助您的柏林之旅
to fund your trip to Berlin.
这怎么可能呢？
And how is that even possible?
不仅仅是划艇
It's not just rowing.
游泳，击剑
Swimming, fencing.
还有许多其他体育运动也在面对...
There are many other sports that are dealing with...
我们到底需要出多少钱？
Exactly how much are we supposed to come up with?
－5000美金　－5000？
- $5,000. - Five?
－一周内？　－一周内
- In a week? - In a week.
如果我们拿不出来呢？
And what if we can't come up with it?
委员会不得不去找
Well, the committee would have to find
合适的接替者去柏林比赛
a suitable replacement to compete in Berlin.
谁合适，亨利？像你的宾大队？
Suitable like who, Henry? Like your Penn squad?
如果有必要，可以
If necessary, yes.
我们当然首先会给加州队一个机会
We'd of course give California the first opportunity.
无论派哪支队去
Either team is a better option
总比不派队好
than not sending a team at all.
这是废话，亨利，都是胡扯
This is bullshit, Henry. It's bullshit.
你没想到我们会赢，但我们赢了
You didn't expect us to win, and we won.
是啊，你们不可能在水上赢我们，你们谁也赢不了
Yeah, you couldn't win on the water. None of you.
我不喜欢这种情况
I don't like this situation.
－现在，你在胡编乱造　－胡说八道
- Now, you're makin' up the rules. - Bullshit.
我也不喜欢这种情况
I don't like the situation
－和你一样　－你当然不喜欢
- any more than you do. - Yeah, sure you don't.
－胡说八道　－我们会解决的
- Bullshit. - We'll figure this out.
我们怎么能拿出5000美元呢？
How are we supposed to come up with $5,000?
我们大学将与校友和支持者联系
Our university will reach out to alumni and boosters.
看看他们能不能支持一点
See if they can scrape anything up.
如果他们的资助也不够呢？
And if they can't find enough?
那就会是加州大学队
Then it'd be Cal
或宾州大学队去了
or Penn.
我们打败了那些家伙
We beat those guys.
我知道
I know.
我们绝不能让那些有钱的混蛋代替我们去
No way we let those rich pricks go instead of us.
那我们最好找点钱出来
Then we better find some money.
是啊
Yeah.
艾尔，你去哪儿？
Al, where you goin'?
帮助将哈士奇队送往柏林
Help send the Huskies to Berlin.
谢谢，祝您愉快
Thank you. You have a nice day.
－谢谢　－好的
- Thank you, sir. - Sure.
嘿，伙计们
Hey, guys.
奥运赛艇队需要您的帮助才能到达柏林
The Olympic rowing team needs your help to get to Berlin.
我们只剩下几天时间了
We only got a couple days left.
伙计们，我有一块钱
Fellas, I got a dollar.
捐助几块钱，帮助我们打败德国人
Spare a couple dollars. Help us beat the Germans.
好的
All right.
谢谢，我叫罗杰
Thanks. My name's Roger.
嘿，我是查克
Hey, I'm Chuck.
哦，拜托
Oh, please.
好吧，你的时间不多了，教练
Well, you're running out of days, Coach.
－你还缺多少，4000？　－3000
- You have what, four left? - Three.
我们的资金才募集到了
And we've only gotten halfway
奥委会说的一半
to what the Olympic Committee says we need.
所以，如果你筹不足钱
So, if you don't raise the money,
你们就得回西雅图去
you go back to Seattle
与此同时，其他队会去柏林？
while some other team goes to Berlin?
正确，这有悖于
Correct. And that goes against
一切体育精神
everything sports should be about.
运动员应该因为表现而得到奖励
Athletes should be rewarded for performance.
不搞政治
No politics,
不搞加分，或者
no adjusted scoring or selection
基于财富和地位来选人
based on wealth and standing.
让最优秀的人获胜
May the best man win.
他们是这么说的，就应该是这样
That's what they say. That's what it should be.
这些孩子，华盛顿的孩子
These boys, Washington's boys,
这个国家的孩子
this country's boys,
我的孩子
my boys,
他们已经证明了自己是最棒的
they have proven themselves to be the best.
帮助我们将哈士奇队送往柏林
Help us send the Huskies to Berlin.
提醒各位，一点一滴都是帮助
A reminder, folks, every little bit helps.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
来吧，支持我们的孩子
Come on, support our boys.
好的，非常感谢
All right. Thank you so much.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
非常感谢，谢谢
Thank you so much. Thank you.
我们从塔科马募集了92美元，以罗杰・莫里斯之名
We got $92 from Tacoma in honor of Roger Morris.
再加上从塞奎姆给乔・兰茨募集的75美元
$75 more from Sequim for Joe Rantz.
从奥林匹亚给唐・休姆募集的90美元
$90 from Olympia for Don Hume.
每个孩子的家乡都付出了努力
Every hometown of these boys has given somethin'.
太平洋电报公司今晚刚寄来250美元
Pacific Telegraph just sent $250 this evening.
我们一共筹集了
Where does that put us
多少了现在？
with everything else we've got?
－嗯，差不多了　－但是呢？
- Eh, close. - But?
好吧，接近就是接近，艾尔
Well, close is just close, Al.
我们没时间了
And we're out of time.
来吧
Come on.
乌尔布里克森太太，我来找你丈夫
Mrs. Ulbrickson, I'm looking for your husband.
我们还有四个小时呢，凯
We still got four hours, Ky.
像往常一样争分夺秒
Racing the clock as usual.
我不能骗你，艾尔
I can't lie to you, Al.
我的孩子们很想去柏林
My boys would love to go to Berlin.
你还缺多少？
How short are you?
300美金
$300.00
左右
Give or take.
嗯
Hmm.
可以吗？
May I?
这是来自加州熊队的
This is from the Cal Bears.
一张300美元的欠条
An IOU for $300.
或多或少
Give or take.
凯
Ky.
除了你的孩子们，没有人有资格去
No one deserves to go but your boys.
先生们
Gentlemen.
乌尔布里克森夫人
Mrs. Ulbrickson.
如果钱还有剩的话，你们可以给我带点纪念品回来
And if there's any extra, you can bring me back a souvenir.
登上，SS，曼哈顿号
Aboard the SS Manhattan,
一船美国运动员驶往汉堡
a shipload of American athletes sails for Hamburg.
奥林匹克运动会，他们的目标
The Olympic Games, their goal.
这是杰西・欧文斯
Here is Jesse Owens,
俄亥俄大学的一个人组成的田径队
the one-man track team from the University of Ohio.
有人说是“有史以来最伟大的”
Some say, "The greatest ever."
300多名运动员将上岸
More than 300 athletes will march ashore
在德国的土地上，准备为金牌而战
on German soil, ready to fight for gold.
参与者包括华盛顿大学的
Among the participants are the University of Washington's
8人赛艇初级队
junior varsity eight-man rowing crew.
这艘小艇已经准备好
The boat is ready to do battle
与意大利、英国
with the likes of Italy, Great Britain
和德国等
and Germany,
最受欢迎的队伍一决高下
all favorites in this most grueling of events.
在柏林，奥运会的筹备工作已经完成
In Berlin, the preparations for the Games are complete,
德国人民已经准备好欢迎
and the German people are ready to welcome
来自52个国家的运动员
athletes from 52 countries.
德国总理阿道夫・希特勒
German Chancellor Adolf Hitler
曾承诺要举办一场无与伦比的盛会
has promised a spectacle like no other,
并计划出席各种活动
and plans to attend a variety of events.
在汉堡，成千上万的德国人欢呼雀跃
In Hamburg, thousands of cheering Germans
欢迎准备上岸的美国人
welcome the Americans as they ready to disembark.
这些业余运动员
These amateur athletes
他们为代表自己的国家做出了巨大牺牲
have sacrificed so much to represent their country,
还有几天奥运会就要开幕了
and as the opening of the Games is just days away,
海内外的美国人
Americans at home and abroad
期待为这些敬业的运动员们加油助威
look forward to rooting for these dedicated athletes.
你好
Hi.
好的
All right.
换好衣服，我们去看看航道
Get changed, we'll go look over the course.
这太棒了
This is great.
还不错
Not bad.
－这就够了　－比在老家强多了
- This'll do. - It's better than back home.
希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler.
记住阿拉莫
Remember the Alamo.
乔，开幕式
Joe, opening ceremony.
快点，你要迟到了
Come on, you're gonna be late.
我想我就不去了
I think I gotta skip.
我太累了
I'm just too tired.
怎么了，有什么问题吗，唐？
Why, what's the problem, Don?
唐感觉不太好
Don doesn't feel so great.
去和其他人会合吧，我留下
Go join the rest. I'll, uh... I'll stay.
我来殿后，你得和你的团队一起走
I'll hang back. You need to walk with your team.
谢谢你，乔治
Thanks, George.
好了，休息吧
All right, get some rest.
吃点东西吧
Try and eat somethin'.
匈牙利
Ungarn.
你是杰西，对吧？杰西・欧文斯？
You're Jesse, right? Jesse Owens?
我是
I am.
你真的是世界上跑得最快的人吗？
You really the fastest man in the world?
－我不知道　－这里的人说
- I don't know. - Folks around here say
你会赢下你参加的每一场比赛
you're gonna win every race you're in.
但愿如此
Well, I hope so.
给德国人点厉害瞧瞧，好吗？
Show those Germans what for, all right?
－不　－不
- No. - No?
不是给德国人
Not the Germans.
是给家乡的父老乡亲的
The folks back home.
美利坚合众国
United States of America.
匈牙利队
The Hungarian team
向德国领导人表示敬意
offering their respect to the German leader.
美国人来了
And here come the Americans.
美国没有敬礼
With no salute from the United States.
听起来孩子们正在交朋友
Sounds like the boys are making friends.
好了，起风了
All right, the winds are up.
这对我们有好处，你们在第二道不受直接影响
That's good for us. You're protected in lane two.
让其他更远的船
Let all the other boats farther out
去对付阵风吧
deal with the gusts.
鲍比，你越是紧守
Bobby, the tighter you hold the line,
比赛就越平稳
the smoother the ride.
现在是三场预赛
Now, three prelims.
每场预赛的获胜者将自动获得总决赛的入场券
The winner of each gets an automatic berth in the finals.
这就是你们想要的，休息一天
That is what you want. You want a day off
让其他球队疲于奔命
and let the other teams wear themselves out
多赛一场
with an extra race.
所以，不要保留
So, do not hold back.
英国队是我们这组值得关注的队伍
Great Britain's the team to watch in our heat.
鲍比，别再来波基普西那招了
Bobby, not another Poughkeepsie.
它们不会像加州队那样后程乏力的
They won't fade like Cal,
所以绝不能让他们领先超过两个艇位
so never let them get more than two lengths up.
伙计们，这是你们应得的
Fellas, you've earned this.
他们不会为风格颁发金牌
They don't give gold medals for style.
唯一重要的是你们在水上的速度有多快
All that matters is how fast you are on the water.
这里没人比你们更快
And nobody here is faster.
蹬腿！
Legs through!
美国人已经领先
And the Americans are already leading
大不列颠半个艇位
by half a boat over Great Britain
优势还在变大
and looking for more.
法国和捷克斯洛伐克紧随其后
Followed by France and Czechoslovakia.
破，划！破，划！
In, through! In, through!
领桨员冉・劳里
Stroke Ran Laurie
正在疯狂地挖掘英国艇的速度
is digging furiously for the British boat.
但是美国人
But the Americans
现在正在大举进攻，扩大领先优势
are pouring it on now, extending their lead.
抬头，破，划
Eyes up. In, through!
划
And through!
只剩100米了
And with only 100 meters to go,
美国人可能正在接近奥运会纪录
the Americans could be closing in on an Olympic record.
抬头
Eyes up!
6分8秒
Six minutes point eight seconds.
新的奥运纪录！
A new Olympic record!
美国赢了！
The United States has won!
你还好吗？嘿，你知道我们赢了吗？
You all right? Hey, you know we won?
－唐，你还好吗？－你知道我们赢了，对吧？嗯？
- Don, are you okay? - You know we won, right? Huh?
－嘿　－来吧
- Hey. - Come on. Come on.
精彩的比赛
Good race.
奥运纪录是个好的开始
Olympic record's a nice start.
但这一切只是为了让我们进入真正重要的比赛
But all that does is get us into the race that matters.
没有人会记得你在预赛中创下的记录
Nobody is gonna remember you set a record at a preliminary.
现在...
Now...
让我们去看看我们要对付的是谁
let's go see what we're up against.
干得好
Good job.
干得好，干得好
Way to go. Way to go.
干得好，孩子们
Good work, boys.
单人赛，双人赛
Singles, doubles,
四人赛，他们还没有输过一场
fours, they haven't lost a race yet.
快
Fast.
唐，来吧
Don, come on.
嘿，走吧
Hey, come on.
你没事吧？
You all right?
教练，教练！
Coach! Coach!
－你还好吗？－没事，我只是累坏了
- You okay? - Mm-hmm. I'm just worn out.
谢谢你，医生，谢谢你的帮助
Thank you, Doctor. Thanks for your help.
怎么说？
What's the word?
某种虫子，他们不确定是什么
Some kind of bug. They're not sure what.
现在，他脱水严重
Right now, he's very dehydrated.
他需要休息
He needs rest.
接下来的24小时，你们都离他远点
And y'all stay away from him for the next 24 hours.
我们不能再失去任何人了
We can't afford losing anybody else.
你说“失去”是什么意思？
What do you mean, "losing"?
如果两天后他还是这样，他就不能参加比赛了
If he's still like this in two days, he's not racing.
决赛航道分配
Lane assignments for the finals.
你不能在比赛中间
You can't change the rules
改变规则
in the middle of a competition!
最快的预赛选手优先选择航道
The fastest qualifiers earn the favored lanes.
一直就是这样
That is the way it's always been.
我们创造了最好的记录
And we posted the best time,
你却把我们困在外面
and you've gone and stuck us on the outside.
这是奥委会决定的航道分配公式
This was the lane formula the committee decided on.
什么时候？就在你们队
When? Right after your squad
划出最慢的排位时间之后？
posted the slowest qualifying time?
小心你的指控，乌尔布里克森教练
Be careful of your accusations, Coach Ulbrickson.
你见过航道上的风，你知道
You've seen the winds on that course and you know
顶风时，有两个长度的劣势
there's a two-length disadvantage when it blows.
我相信你的艇员们会处理好的
I'm sure your crew will manage.
天气预报预计今天会风平浪静
The forecasters expect a calm day.
嗯...
Well...
我们对此表示抗议
We'll protest this.
记下了，祝你好运
Noted. And good luck.
好了，听好了，孩子们
All right. Listen up, boys.
这条航道很难走，所以你们开始时得快点
It's a tough lane, so you gotta start quick.
必须让他们在你的视线范围内
You gotta keep them in sight.
最后500米那里，风会被挡住
That wind will be blocked for the last 500 meters.
这就是你们的机会
And that's your shot.
这就是你们拿下他们的地方
That's where you're gonna take 'em,
但前提是，你们得让他们保持在视线范围内
but only if you keep 'em in sight.
听着，每一支球队
Listen, every one of those teams
为了这一刻，他们训练了一辈子
have trained their whole lives for this moment.
它们都是富家子
They're all legacies.
我们不是
We're not.
为了祖国
Row for your country.
为了彼此
Row for each other.
为了一切不利因素
Row for that one moment when everything
都退避三舍的那一刻
that's stacked against you can take a back seat.
无论结果如何，我都为你们感到骄傲
For what it's worth, I'm proud of you boys.
好了，出发吧
All right, push off.
什么？
What?
没事
Nothin'
他们还不如把我们扔
They might as well have stuck us
在北大西洋上
out on the North Atlantic.
成千上万的人正在入座
Thousands of people are taking their seats,
男子组八人决赛
gathered for the Men's Eights finals.
世界上最好的六支赛艇队
The world's six best rowing teams
为金牌进行最后的角逐
in one last race for the gold.
德国，意大利，匈牙利
Germany, Italy, Hungary
德国在单人，双人和四人比赛中摘得金牌
Germany has taken gold in singles, doubles, and fours,
他们正在追求大满贯
and they're looking for a sweep.
瑞士，英国和美国
Switzerland, Great Britain, and the United States
位列前六
round out the six.
来自华盛顿的男孩们如此接近于
The boys from Washington so close
将奥运冠军带回西雅图
to bringing an Olympic title back to Seattle.
德国！德国！
Deutschland! Deutschland!
德国！德国！德国！德国！
Deutschland! Deutschland! Deutschland! Deutschland!
德国！德国！
Deutschland! Deutschland!
德国！德国！德国！德国！
Deutschland! Deutschland! Deutschland! Deutschland!
德国！德国！
Deutschland! Deutschland!
唐，你还好吗？
Don, you okay?
你能行的，唐，好吗？
You got this, Don, all right?
嘿，他说什么？
Hey, what'd he say?
好吧，来吧，让我们赢下这一场
All right. Come on, let's win this.
桨准备好了
Oars ready.
来吧
Come on.
好吧，我们有两段风
All right, we got two lengths of wind
来弥补这差距
to make up on this bunch.
所以，我们从38拍开始
So, we start at 38.
鲍比，鲍比
Bobby! Bobby!
妈的！划！
Shit! Row! Row!
来吧
Come on.
哦，上帝啊，他听不到
Oh, God! He couldn't hear him.
美国人一出场就跌跌撞撞
The Americans have stumbled out of the gate,
已经落到了最后
already a full boat behind.
蹬腿
Legs through.
好的，现在换到30拍
All right, now move to 30.
走！破，划
Go! In, through.
蹬腿
Legs through!
破，划，破
In, through! In!
好吧，我们有38拍
All right. We got 38!
给我40拍
Give me 40!
破，划
In, through!
破，划，上
In, through! Go!
快点，唐，加速
Come on, Don, pick it up.
腿用力，破，划
In the legs! In, through!
破，划
In, through!
－破，划！－是时候行动了
- In, through! - It's time to move!
来吧，唐
Come on, Don.
去，唐
Go, Don!
来吧，孩子们
Come on, boys.
德国仅次于意大利
Germany is just behind Italy,
英国紧随其后
followed by Great Britain.
美国仍然排在最后，远远落后于匈牙利
The U.S. still in last, well behind Hungary.
给我加速！必须加速
Give me more! Gotta have more!
来吧，唐，给我40拍
Come on, Don. Give me 40.
腿用力
In the legs.
加油，唐，加油，唐
Push it, Don. Come on, Don!
现在是个好时机，休姆
Now would be a good time, Hume!
来吧，唐！振作起来
Come on, Don! Pick it up!
唐，来吧
Don, come on.
来吧，唐
Come on, Don.
给我40拍，你可以的
Gotta give me 40. You have it.
把它给我
Give it to me.
来吧，给我40拍
Come on, give me 40.
来吧，唐
Come on, Don.
来吧
Come on!
唐
Don!
唐，来吧
Don! Come on!
每天清晨，每天傍晚
Every morning, every evening
我们玩得开心吗？
Ain't we got fun?
钱不多，哦，但是亲爱的
Not much money, oh, but honey
我们不是有...吗？
Ain't we got...
没错，唐给我40拍
That's right, Don! Give me 40!
去吧，划
Go! Through!
蹬腿
Legs through!
抬头
Eyes up!
放低！
Stay low!
－放松　－来了
- Stay loose! - And here comes
爆裂的美国
the United States with a burst.
摇
Row!
同步
As one!
接近500米大关
Nearing the 500-meter mark,
美国人赶上了
the Americans have caught up
匈牙利队和瑞士队
to the Hungarian and Swiss teams.
保持
Stay!
划，破，划
And through! In, through!
美国人已经超越
The Americans have overtaken
瑞士艇和匈牙利艇
the Swiss and the Hungarian boats.
德国和意大利共同领先
Germany and Italy share the lead,
英国紧随其后
with Great Britain trailing.
腿放松
Legs loose!
破，划
In, through!
In and through!
四，五！
Four! Five!
破，划
In, through!
给我42拍
Give me 42!
现在
Now!
破，划
In, through!
呼吸！
Breathe!
蹬腿，破，划
Legs through! In, through!
还有15桨！划
Fifteen more! In!
来吧，划
Come on. Through!
再来10桨
Ten more!
肩膀向下，放松
Shoulders down and loose.
抬高
Stand tall!
破，划
In, through!
美国人继续强悍
And the Americans continue strong,
超越英国队，获得第三名
moving past Great Britain and headed for third.
美国正在向奖牌位置迈进
The U.S. is moving into medal position.
划！抬头
Through! Eyes up!
破，划
In, through!
给我46拍
Give me 46!
冲
Go!
300米，美国人
300 meters, and the Americans
追上了！
have pulled even!
现在三条艇齐头并进
The boats are three across now.
还剩250米
250 meters to go.
来吧，来吧，来吧
Come on, come on, come on.
蹬腿
Legs through!
这是三艇角逐
It's a three-boat race.
谁将会胜出？
Who's going to break?
是德国，意大利
It's Germany, Italy.
意大利，德国
Italy, Germany.
美国和意大利
The U.S. and Italy.
太接近了
It's just too close.
放低
Stay low!
还剩100米
100 meters to go.
不相上下
It's neck and neck.
来吧
Come on.
德国！德国！
Deutschland! Deutschland!
德国！德国！德国！德国！
Deutschland! Deutschland! Deutschland! Deutschland!
破，划
In, through!
倾尽全力！冲
Give it everything! Go!
保持中心位置！
Stay central!
抬头
Eyes up!
同步
As one!
跟上你面前的人
Off the man in front of you!
破，划
In, through!
去吧，破，划
Go! In, through!
抬头
Eyes up!
腿用力
In the legs!
德国！德国！
Deutschland! Deutschland!
德国，意大利，美国
Germany, Italy, America.
德国！德国
Deutschland! Deutschland!
就这样！
And that's it!
就是这样！
That's it!
结果太接近了，记者无法判断
The results are just too close for this reporter to tell.
来吧
Come on.
谁赢了？
Who won?
德国粉丝相信
The German fans believe
是他们赢得了1936年奥运会的第六场胜利
they've got their sixth win of these 1936 Olympics.
我们只能坐等结果
We can only sit and wait for the results.
你看到了吗？
Did you see?
美国
America.
美国队赢得了金牌！
The United States has won the gold!
干得好，约翰尼
Good job, Johnny.
我们成功了，孩子们！
We did it, boys!
来吧
Come on!
激动人心的一桨
One hell of a stroke.
美国做到了！
America has done it!
他们赢得了金牌
They've won the gold!
真是一场精彩的比赛
Hell of a race.
－你做到了，艾尔，你做到了　－我为你骄傲
- You did it, Al. You did it. - I'm proud of you.
我们做到了
We did it.
这个怎么样？
How about this, huh?
嗯，这个怎么样？
Mm-hmm. How about this?
关于那些男孩，你有什么想说的吗，艾尔？
Anything you'd like to say about those boys, Al?
他们是我见过的最棒的艇员
They are the finest I ever saw seated in a shell.
不错吧，伙计们？
Not bad, huh, fellas?
你看到了吗？
Did you see that?
艇直接把我推到了岸边
Boat pushed me right into the bank.
－看看这个　－别担心，我们会修好的
- Look at this. - Don't worry, we'll fix it.
嘿，爷爷？
Hey, Grandpa?
你觉得有一天我会划艇吗？
You think someday I can row crew?
嗯，你得坚持下去
Well, you gotta keep at it.
你喜欢八人划艇吗？
Did you like rowing eight-man crew?
－八个人　－对
- Eight? - Yeah.
我们从来不是八个人
We were never eight.
我们是一个人
We were one.
字幕：Dex7er（公众号：值得看的）